John Howard Society of the Lower Mainland of British Columbia fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- General Administrative and Office Files, 1922 - 1973; F-1-2; 1.66 m of textual records
  - Administration, 1931 - 1969; F-1-2-1; 38 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files relating to general administrative matters of the Society, including general reports, organizational information, policies and agreements. Files also include some committee files, such as the Constitution, Provincial Liaison and Women's and Family Committees. Files in this subseries include reports, memoranda, articles, newspaper clippings and pamphlets, and correspondence.
    - Organization and Management, 1961; F-1-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
      Restricted in whole
    - Board of Directors (1946-1968), F-1-2-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Committees and Departments, 1967 - 1968; F-1-2-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Capital Punishment Committee, 1956 - 1957; F-1-2-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Constitution Committee, 1932 - 1958; F-1-2-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Institutions Committee, 1955 - 1964; F-1-2-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Penitentiary Committee Minutes, 1956 - 1959; F-1-2-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Legal Aid Committee, 1950 - 1956; F-1-2-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Provincial Liaison Committee, 1956 - 1968; F-1-2-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Rehabilitation Committee, 1951 - 1953; F-1-2-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Women's and Family Committee, 1955 - 1957; F-1-2-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Research Committee, 1958 - 1965; F-1-2-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Education Committee, 1963 - 1965; F-1-2-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Welfare Grants, 1967 - 1968; F-1-2-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Royal Commission to Examine Welfare Services, 1961 - 1964; F-1-2-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Meetings, Conferences and Visits Conventions, 1963 - 1968; F-1-2-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Annual Meetings 1947-1957, F-1-2-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-12)
    - Annual Meeting and Luncheon (1963), F-1-2-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Annual Meetings 1958-1967, F-1-2-1-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Annual Meeting 1968-1969, F-1-2-1-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Executive Meetings 1955-1961, F-1-2-1-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Staff Meetings, 1955 - 1968; F-1-2-1-0-22 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Conference on Juvenile Delinquency, 1956 - 1963; F-1-2-1-0-23 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Projects, Policies and Agreements, 1961 - 1964; F-1-2-1-0-24 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Functions, 1932 - 1951; F-1-2-1-0-25 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Office Procedure, 1963; F-1-2-1-0-26 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - John Howard Players, 1963 - 1964; F-1-2-1-0-27 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Wives' Group, 1959 - 1967; F-1-2-1-0-28 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Inter-provincial Referrals, 1964 - 1966; F-1-2-1-0-29 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Compensation to Victims of Crime, 1967; F-1-2-1-0-30 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Correspondence - (1948-49), 1948 - 1949; F-1-2-1-0-31 (Archival box - standard 1-13)
    - Correspondence - (1950-51), 1950 - 1951; F-1-2-1-0-32 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Correspondence - (1952-53), 1952 - 1953; F-1-2-1-0-33 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Correspondence - (1954), F-1-2-1-0-34 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Public Relations and Information - General, 1953 - 1958; F-1-2-1-0-35 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1940 - 1965; F-1-2-1-0-36 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Historical Data, 1931 - 1955; F-1-2-1-0-37 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Newsletters - Correspondence, 1967 - 1968; F-1-2-1-0-38 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Newsletters - Okanagan Mainline, 1961 - 1964; F-1-2-1-0-39 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Press Releases, 1967 - 1969; F-1-2-1-0-40 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Charts, F-1-2-1-0-41 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Statistics - General, 1931 - 1955; F-1-2-1-0-42 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Service Reports 1946-1953 - Community Chest and Council, F-1-2-1-0-43 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Service Reports 1954 - Community Chest and Council, F-1-2-1-0-44 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Service Reports - Remission Service, Ottawa, 1932 - 1957; F-1-2-1-0-45 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Service Reports - Commissioner of Penitentiaries, 1931 - 1964; F-1-2-1-0-46 (Archival box - standard 1-14)
    - Service Reports - Provincial Government, 1956 - 1958; F-1-2-1-0-47 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
  - Corrections - General, 1931 - 1965; F-1-2-2; 8 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files pertaining to corrections reform, including correspondence with and information about international organizations involved in the areas of prison reform and criminal rehabilitation, such as the Howard League for Penal Reform in Great Britain. Files also include information about various correctional institutions outside of B.C., and include articles, newspapers, clippings, bulletins, reports and correspondence.
    Howard League for Penal Reform
    - Corrections - Canada, 1933 - 1965; F-1-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Penal Reform, 1934 - 1965; F-1-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Archambault Report (J.H.S. and C.P.A. Submissions), 1936; F-1-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Juvenile Delinquency, 1932 - 1964; F-1-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Penal Commission, 1939 - 1942; F-1-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Corrections - U.S.A., 1933 - 1957; F-1-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Howard League, 1931 - 1965; F-1-2-2-0-7
  - Elizabeth Fry, 1953 - 1966; F-1-2-3; 1 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of a single file on the Elizabeth Fry Society. File consists mainly of correspondence, but also includes miscellaneous materials, such as Annual Reports, lists of Society officers, newspaper clippings and statistical information about women received at Oakalla Prison.
    Elizabeth Fry Society
    - Elizabeth Fry Society, 1953 - 1966; F-1-2-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
  - Finances, 1947 - 1968; F-1-2-4; 4 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files on various financial matters, such as revenue, including briefs submitted by the Society to government agencies in support of requests for financial aid; banking, including lists of signing officers; and budgets, including correspondence with Community Chest and Council Budget Committee.
    - Revenue - Provincial Government (Acknowledgments of Monthly Grants), 1962 - 1968; F-1-2-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-15)
    - Banking - Signing Officers, 1952 - 1963; F-1-2-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Budget - 1947-65 - Community Chest and Councils, 1947 - 1965; F-1-2-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
  - Health and Related Subjects, 1933 - 1972; F-1-2-5; 8 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files on various health-related subjects, such as disabled veterans, drug addiction and venereal disease. Files typically include newspaper clippings, pamphlets, brochures, briefs and statistical information on these health-related topics.
    - Alcoholism, 1934 - 1959; F-1-2-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Drug Addiction, 1937 - 1972; F-1-2-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Traffic In Narcotics - Brief, 1955; F-1-2-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Venereal Disease, 1933 - 1955; F-1-2-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Mental Hospitals, 1951 - 1967; F-1-2-5-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Disabled Veterans, 1943; F-1-2-5-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
  - Institutions, 1931 - 1973; F-1-2-6; 24 cm of textual records 1 Photograph; Physical description: 1 photograph located in F-1-2-6-11
    Subseries consists of files on various correctional institutions, including Haney Correctional Institution, The Oakalla Prison Farm and the B.C. Penitentiary (see Access Points for list). Files include reports, memoranda, notes, newspaper clippings and correspondence relating to the operation and management of the various penitentiaries in B.C.
    British Columbia Penitentiary; Kingston Penitentiary; Stony Mountain Institutition; Saskatchewan Penitentiary; Oakalla Prison Farm; Haney Correctional Institute; Kamloops Jail; Prince George Jail; Brannan Lake School for Boys
    - Penitentiaries, 1931 - 1964; F-1-2-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-16)
    - Commissioner of Penitentiaries, 1934 - 1973; F-1-2-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - After-Care Function Relative to Penitentiaries, 1962 - 1965; F-1-2-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - B.C. Penitentiary - (including William Head and Aggassiz), 1940 - 1967; F-1-2-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - B.C. Penitentiary - Visiting and Correspondence, 1933 - 1968; F-1-2-6-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - B.C. Penitentiary - Inmate Welfare Committee and Service Clubs, 1956 - 1965; F-1-2-6-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - B.C. Penitentiary - Medical Facilities, 1951 - 1967; F-1-2-6-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Kingston Penitentiary, 1954 - 1967; F-1-2-6-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Manitoba Penitentiary, 1949 - 1957; F-1-2-6-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Saskatchewan Penitentiary, 1935 - 1965; F-1-2-6-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Oakalla Prison Farm, 1946 - 1964; F-1-2-6-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
      Textual records; Photographic materials
    - Oakalla Meetings, 1957 - 1958; F-1-2-6-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Prison Visiting - Pan-Abode Unit, 1958 - 1959; F-1-2-6-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Prison Medical Services, 1967 - 1968; F-1-2-6-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-17)
    - Haney Correctional Institution, 1957 - 1965; F-1-2-6-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Haney Correctional Institution - Admissions, 1957 - 1958; F-1-2-6-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Haney Correctional Institution - Pre-Release Advisory Committee, 1961; F-1-2-6-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Gold Creek Camp, 1957 - 1962; F-1-2-6-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Kamloops Gaol, 1933 - 1958; F-1-2-6-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Prince George Gaol, 1947 - 1967; F-1-2-6-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - City Gaols and Police Departments, 1933 - 1967; F-1-2-6-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Prisons for Women, 1955 - 1957; F-1-2-6-0-22 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Pre-Release Camps, 1958 - 1959; F-1-2-6-0-23 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Borstal, 1947 - 1962; F-1-2-6-0-24 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Industrial Schools, 1955 - 1956; F-1-2-6-0-25 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Brannan Lake School for Boys (Formerly Boys' Industrial School), 1934; 1950-1957; F-1-2-6-0-26 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
  - John Howard Societies, 1930 - 1968; F-1-2-7; 37 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files on other offices of the John Howard Society: its National office, provincial counterparts and regional branches. National office files contain material relevant to its formation around 1961 and provincial and regional files relate to matters of common concern, including policy matters. Files also contain information about these organizations, including reports and other printed material.
    John Howard Society of Alberta; John Howard Society of Canada; John Howard Society of Manitoba; John Howard Society of New Brunswick; John Howard Society of Newfoundland; John Howard Society of Nova Scotia; John Howard Society of Ontario; John Howard Society of Prince Edward Island; John Howard Society of Quebec; John Howard Society of Saskatchewan; John Howard Society of the Lower Mainland of British Columbia
    - John Howard Society of B.C., 1956 - 1965; F-1-2-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Vancouver Island, 1930 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - New Westminster, 1955 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - New Westminster Committee Minutes, 1955 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-18)
    - Okanagan-Mainline Operations, 1961 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Okanagan Branch, 1955 - 1957; F-1-2-7-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Kamloops Branch, 1961 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Kelowna Branch, 1961 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Penticton Branch, 1957 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Vernon Branch, 1957 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Prince George Branch, 1957 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Cranbrook and East Kootenay, 1957 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-19)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Nelson and District Branch, 1957 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of B.C. - Trail and Castlegar Branch, 1957 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Alberta, 1948 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Saskatchewan, 1940 - 1964; F-1-2-7-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Manitoba, 1953 - 1965; F-1-2-7-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Ontario, 1931 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Quebec, 1944 - 1965; F-1-2-7-0-19 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Nova Scotia, 1955 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-20 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Newfoundland, 1950 - 1955; F-1-2-7-0-21 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of National Organization, 1958 - 1962; F-1-2-7-0-22 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Canada (Mar. 1962 - Dec. 31, 1962), F-1-2-7-0-23 (Archival box - standard 1-20)
    - John Howard Society of Canada, 1963; F-1-2-7-0-24 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - John Howard Society of Canada, 1964; F-1-2-7-0-25 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - John Howard Society of Canada, 1965; F-1-2-7-0-26 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - John Howard Society of Canada (May 1966-67 - 1968), 1966 - 1968; F-1-2-7-0-27 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - John Howard Society of Prince Edward Island, 1961; F-1-2-7-0-28 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - John Howard Society of New Brunswick, 1963; F-1-2-7-0-29 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
  - Law and Legal Matters, 1934 - 1968; F-1-2-8; 6 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files pertaining to various legal matters, including family court, legal aid and transportation issues. Files include reports, brochures, pamphlets and correspondence.
    - Legislation, 1944 - 1965; F-1-2-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - Transportation Rules, 1953 - 1958; F-1-2-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - Provincial Legislation, 1964; F-1-2-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-21)
    - Family Court, 1934 - 1961; F-1-2-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Legal Aid, 1950 - 1968; F-1-2-8-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
  - Misconduct and Treatment, 1931 - 1968; F-1-2-9; 11 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of files related to the misconduct and treatment of offenders, including young offenders, sexual offenders and habitual offenders.
    - Juvenile Delinquency, 1941 - 1950; F-1-2-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Committee on Juvenile Delinquency 1962, F-1-2-9-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Young Offenders, 1931 - 1945; F-1-2-9-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Sex Offenders, 1947 - 1964; F-1-2-9-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Habitual Offenders, 1964; F-1-2-9-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Treatment and After-care, 1958, 1964; F-1-2-9-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Probation, 1934 - 1959; F-1-2-9-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Meetings - Correctional Planning Committee, 1958 - 1960; F-1-2-9-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Parole, 1948 - 1964; F-1-2-9-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Remission Service, 1942 - 1958; F-1-2-9-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-22)
    - Capital Punishment, 1943 - 1968; F-1-2-9-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
  - Personnel and Labour Conditions, 1941 - 1963; F-1-2-10; 1 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of a single file on unemployment insurance. The file contains miscellaneous materials pertaining to unemployment insurance coverage for inmates and proposed amendments to the Unemployment Insurance Act.
    - Unemployment Insurance, 1941 - 1963; F-1-2-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
  - Resources and Services - Health and Related Subjects, 1952 - 1968; F-1-2-11; 2 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of 2 health-related files: one is on the Alcoholism Foundation, containing general printed material on the Foundation, such as newsletters, newspaper clippings, reports and some correspondence; the other is on narcotics, consisting primarily of correspondence with government committees, doctors and associations.
    Alcoholism Foundation
    - Alcoholism Foundation, 1952 - 1959; F-1-2-11-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Narcotics, 1964 - 1968; F-1-2-11-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
  - Social Work, 1943 - 1969; F-1-2-12; 1 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of a single file on social work. The file contains miscellaneous articles, reports and correspondence with various institutions, such as the Department of Social Work at the University of British Columbia and the Vancouver Council on Social Agencies.
    - Social Work - General, 1943 - 1969; F-1-2-12-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
  - General and Miscellaneous, 1931 - 1957; F-1-2-13; 2 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of 2 files: one is a general John Howard Society file containing general reports on the Society, memoranda and correspondence with those interested in the work of the Society; and the other contains information on prison libraries, especially the Society's work in advocating the role of prison libraries in the rehabilitation of offenders.
    - John Howard Society - General, 1932 - 1957; F-1-2-13-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Prison Libraries, 1931 - 1950; F-1-2-13-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
  - Resources and Services, 1922 - 1969; F-1-2-14; 23 cm of textual records
    Subseries consists of a number of files on reports and statistics of services provided by the Society, such as the number of cases accepted and cases closed, areas of services and work distribution. A number of other files in this subseries contain material on related associations of the Society, including the B.C. Borstal Association, Canadian Penal Association and the Canadian Corrections Association (see Access Points for list).
    British Columbia Borstall Association; Canadian Penal Association; National Prisoners Aid Association; International Prisoners Aid Association; British Columbia Youth Council; Canadian Corrections Association; Vancouver Clothing Committee; Ex-Convicts Anonymous; Central City Mission
    - UCS Priorities, 1962 - 1969; F-1-2-14-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Agency Agreements, 1922 - 1968; F-1-2-14-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Reports and Statistics, 1954 - 1958; F-1-2-14-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Reports and Statistics, 1957; F-1-2-14-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Reports and Statistics, 1956; F-1-2-14-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Reports and Statistics, 1954 - 1955; F-1-2-14-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - Reports and Statistics, 1959; F-1-2-14-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-23)
    - B.C. Borstall Association, 1948 - 1963; F-1-2-14-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - Canadian Penal Association (discontinued), 1951 - 1968; F-1-2-14-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - National Prisoners Aid Association, 1934 - 1948; F-1-2-14-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - International Prisoners Aid Association, 1940 - 1959; F-1-2-14-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - B.C. Youth Council, 1956 - 1958; F-1-2-14-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - B.C. Youth Council - Constitution, 1952 - 1958; F-1-2-14-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - Canadian Corrections Association, 1959 - 1961; F-1-2-14-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-24)
    - Central City Mission, 1950 - 1959; F-1-2-14-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Vancouver Clothing Committee, 1948 - 1954; F-1-2-14-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Ex-Convicts Anonymous, 1956 - 1957; F-1-2-14-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
- General administrative and office files, 1934 - 1990; F-1-3; 3.08 m of textual records
  Series consists of the administrative files of the Society from about 1969 to 1982. During this period, a new file classification plan was in place where each file category or subject area was assigned a unique numeric code.
  - Administration, 1930 - 1990; F-1-3-1; 91 cm of textual records 45 photographs
    Subseries consists of general administrative files, including committee information, conference materials, newsletters, board of directors minutes, scholarship fund records, correspondence, union-related records, and other general office files.
    - The John Howard Society of British Columbia - General, 1962 - 1980; F-1-3-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Board of Directors - Planning Committee, 1980; F-1-3-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Executive Committee, 1980; F-1-3-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee - B.C. Penitentiary 1976-79, 1976 - 1979; F-1-3-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Citizens Advisory Committee - General, 1978 - 1979; F-1-3-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Office Administration - General, 1972 - 1980; F-1-3-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Public Information, 1967 - 1974; F-1-3-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 1-25)
    - Conference, Visits and Meetings - vol. 1 (1969-1974), F-1-3-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Annual Meetings - 1969-1976, F-1-3-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Dinner Meetings, 1969 - 1972; F-1-3-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Registrar of Companies 1934-1968, F-1-3-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Registrar of Companies 1969-1980, F-1-3-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Newsletters 1969-1973 vol. 1 nos. 43-63, F-1-3-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Newsletter Index, 1958 - 1973; F-1-3-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 1-26)
    - Book Reviews (J.D. Hobden Book Miss J.B. Witton), 1973 - 1974; F-1-3-1-0-15 (Archival box - standard 1-27)
    - Newsletters 1958-1968 vol. 1 nos. 1-42, F-1-3-1-0-16 (Archival box - standard 1-27)
    - Personnel - Staff Reports, 1974 - 1978; F-1-3-1-0-17 (Archival box - standard 1-27)
    - Union Contracts - June 1/76-80, 1975 - 1980; F-1-3-1-0-18 (Archival box - standard 1-27)
    - Unarchived, 1930-1969; F-1-3-1-1; 2 cm of textual records
      Subseries consists of two files labelled 'unarchived' regarding the Society's constitutional changes from the 1930s and problems from the 1960s.
      - 1960-1969 Other problems / Alberta, F-1-3-1-1-1 (Archival box - standard 1-91)